時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸며, 태어나 처음으로 미야모토 마을을 떠난 무사시는
Dreaming to become the number one Karakuri martial artist, Musashi left Miyamoto village for the first time,
보쿠덴 아래에서 수련을 받고, 고조의 다리에서 벤케이하고 싸웠지만
trained under Bokuden, and fought against Benkei on the bridge of the capital city,
악전고투 끝에 우시와카에게 좋은 걸 놓쳐버렸을 뿐이었다.
but after a hard struggle, Ushiwaka ended up claiming the good stuff.
료마는 혼자 바람 속에
Ryoma is Alone in the Wind
아야야.
Ouch!
뭐오?
What is it-dasu?
어라, 발로 차 버려서 미안하오.
Sorry for kicking-dasu.
신경쓰지 마.
No need to worry.
그래도...
But...
료마
Ryoma
사나이는 그런 조그마한 것에 신경쓰지 말고 속이 넓어야지.
A man shouldn't be bothered by that; instead, one should be large-hearted!
저... 뭘 보시오?
Uh... what are you looking at-dasu?
구름이야.
Clouds.
구름?
Clouds?
구름은 좋지. 어디에도 얽매이지 않고 넓은 하늘을 마음대로 흘러 다니고 있으니.
I envy clouds. They are never tied to anything, and they wander around the sky as they desire.
넌 지금 어딜 가니?
Where will you be heading to?
검의 수련을 위해 요시오카 도장에 가고 있던 길이오.
I am going to Yoshioka Dōjō to train my swordsmanship-dasu.
검의 수련! 세상은 칼이 필요없는 시대가 되어가고 있어.
Swordsmanship! The world is losing the need of swords.
그럴 리가 없소. 어떤 시대라도 검의 길을 끝까지 걸어가는 것은 카라쿠리 무예가에게 있어 영원의 목표라오.
That's impossible-dasu. For any Karakuri martial artist, reaching the extremes of swords is the eternal aim-dasu.
작군, 작아! 사나이라면 이 지팡구국을 바꿀 꿈을 가져야지.
Small. That's small! If you call yourself a man, you should dream to change this Jipangu State!
낮잠을 자고 있어 이상한 꿈을 꾸고 계시는 것 같소.
I think you're having some strange dreams from a nap-dasu.
나, 서둘러야 하니 먼저 실례하겠소.
I have to hurry, so excuse me-dasu.
아이 주제에 옛날을 사는 놈이군!
He's living in the past, for a kid!
이곳은 미야코 궁전. 무사시는 잠시 이 마을에 머물고 있었다.
This is the Miyako Palace. Musashi was staying in this village for the time being.
어딜 봐서 검의 시대가 끝난다는 것이오?
What makes him think that the era of sword is going to end-dasu?
잠깐 멈춰라, 꼬맹아!
Stop! You there!
콘도
Kondō
이 주변에선 본 적 없는 얼굴이군. 넌 누구냐!
I never saw you around here before. Identify yourself!
잠, 잠깐 기다리시오! 사람을 찾을 때에는 먼저 자신의 이름이 예의가 아니오!
Ju- just a moment-dasu! Aren't you forgetting your manners by not telling your name before finding people-dasu?
뭐라고, 건방진 꼬맹이놈! 이 신선조의 콘도 국장을 모른다는 소리냐!
What did you say, you impudent kid?! Don't you know Kondō, the chief of Shinsen Family?
그런 것이었소. 나는 무사시라고 불리는 자이오.
Is that it-dasu? I am Musashi-dasu.
뭐, 뭐... 그렇게 고분고분하게 말하면 됐다.
Um, well... It's alright. I see that you're a honest guy.
어쨌든 너, 이 자를 본 적이 있나?
Anyway, did you see this guy before?
어? 아, 이 사람!
Huh? I remember!
이 녀석을 아나?
Do you know this guy?
아까 서쪽 풀밭에서 봤소.
I saw him on a lawn at west-dasu.
젠장, 그 놈, 그런 곳에 숨어있던 것인가!
Damn, that bastard! So that's where he was hiding at!
-너희 모두 서둘러라!
-예!
-Everyone, hurry!
-Got it!
자, 잠깐 기다리시오! 그 자는 무슨 일을 했소?
Ju- just a moment-dasu! What did he do-dasu?
그 녀석은 이 미야코 궁전을 뒤엎고자 반란을 꾀하는 극악한 범죄자다!
He is a crime who's planning to rebel against the Miyako Palace!
그런 나쁜 사람으로는 안 보였소만...
I didn't thought he was a bad person-dasu...
(주) 요시오카 도장
Yoshioka Dōjō Inc.
이곳에 요시오카류 도장의 대두목이 있소!
The chief of the Yoshioka Family Dōjō must be here-dasu!
그 때는 방심했지만 이번엔 지지 않겠소!
I was careless that time, but I won't lose this time-dasu!
누구 있소?
Excuse me-dasu!
뭔 일이냐?
What's your business?
난 무술 수행중인 무사시라고 불리는 자이오!
I am Musashi, traveling about to gain skill in combat-dasu!
요시오카 도장의 사람과 시합이 하고 싶어 왔소!
I came to have a match against a person from Yoshioka Dōjō-dasu!
너같은 아가가 전국에 몇만 명의 생도가 있는 우리 요시오카 도장에 시합을 하고 싶단 게냐!
You're asking to have a match against tens of thousands of us at Yoshioka Dōjō, kid?
검의 길에는 나이는 관계가 없소. 대단한 자가 이기오!
Age does not hinder the path of sword-dasu. A better one wins-dasu!
뭐라니, 이 애새끼가! 기껏 친절하게 대해 주었더니! 이 내가 지겹도록 때려주길 바라니?
What did you say, you brat? I was being kind and you still want to be whipped to death?
아, 잠깐. 이런 얘한테 화내서 어쩌려고.
Now, now. He's just a kid. Chill out.
너같은 얘를 도장에 들일 생각은 없다. 자, 돌아가라, 돌아가!
We are no way letting a kid like you enter the Dōjō. Go back home.
아, 부탁드리오! 시합을!
Please-dasu! A match!
조금이라도!
Even for a bit!
저...
Excuse...
좋소! 이렇게 되었다면 뭐가 어떻게 되더라도 시합을 하고야 말겠소!
I'll do whatever it takes to have a match against them-dasu!
좋은 물고기~ 물고기~ 물고기~
Anybody want to buy some fishes? Fishes to sell!
싱싱한 물고기요~
Fresh fishes!
열심히 일하고 나서 피곤한 몸에 좋은 물고기라오~
These fishes are good for your body after the tiring work!
저기, 물고기 아저씨. 통 하나 분량만큼 주세요.
Hey, Mr. Fisher, I'd like to buy the amount of one basket.
예, 감사드리오!
Thank you-dasu.
잘 됐소!
This went well-dasu!
물고기 아저씨, 이 쪽이에요!
This way, Mr. Fisher!
어라? 어디 갔지?
Huh? Where did he go?
잘 찾아왔소.
I made it-dasu.
어이, 너! 어디에 가나!
Hey, you! Where are you going?
저, 물고기 배달하러 왔소이만, 길을 잃어버렸소.
I'm here to deliver the fishes, but I got lost-dasu.
길을 잃었다고?
You got lost?
멍청한 소리 마라! 뒷문에서 부엌까지는 아주 조금이다!
Are you joking? The kitchen and the back door are very close!
아니, 그게... 저, 스페셜한 방향치라서...
Er, to be exact-dasu, I'm a special kind of not having sense of directions...
그래도... 이래도 괜찮소. 자, 빨리 전달하고 돌아가겠소.
But... it'll be all right-dasu. I'll deliver this and go back right away-dasu.
-잠깐 멈춰라!
-수상한 놈이다. 도장에 데려가서 알아보겠다!
-Stop right there!
-Suspicious. We'll take you to Dōjō and find out who you are!
뭐냐, 이 녀석은?
Who is this guy?
예, 저택 안을 헤매고 있던 수상한 자입니다, 세주로 님.
Yessir, he is a suspicious man wandering around inside the estate, Master Sējūrō.
어쩌면 도둑일 지도 모릅니다.
He might be a thief as well.
내 도장에 몰래 들어오다니, 적반하장은 널 말하는군.
To creep into my Dōjō, you are a good example of the expression the guilty are audacious.
그 목, 바로 잘라 주겠다!
I'll cut off your neck right now!
그, 그게 아니오! 전 시합을 하고 싶어 몰래 들어왔을 뿐이오!
No, that's not it-dasu! I just wanted to have a match so I crept in and that's all-dasu!
넌 아까 그 애송이!
You're that stupid brat!
뭐냐, 오카야마에서 뭇매맞은 꼬맹이 아니냐! 또 당하러 왔나?
You're that kid beaten in Okayama! Are you here to be beaten again?
난 쓰라린 수련을 받아 더 이상 그 때의 내가 아니오!
After the painful training, I am now different from me of the past-dasu!
좋다! 그 정도로 이 요시오카 도장과 시합을 하고 싶다면 내가 직접 상대를 해 주지.
Good then! If you really want that much to have a match against this Yoshioka Dōjō, I'll fight you myself.
시합을 해주실 것이오?
Are you going to be my opponent-dasu?
좋다.
Yes.
굳이 형님이 이 녀석하고 시합을 해도...
You don't really have to fight against this kid, brother.
설마, 만일 지는 일이 있다면 이 요시오카의 간판에 상처가 납니다!
If you end up losing for some reason, the name of our Yoshioka family will be scratched!
걱정하지 마라! 이런 꼬맹이에게 내가 질 리가 없지 않은가!
Don't worry! There's no way I'm losing to such a brat!
But! If you lose to me, you must shout Yoshioka Dōjō is strong as expected around the town!
그 대신! 내가 지면 요시오카 도장은 역시 강했다고 말하며 돌아다녀야 할 것이다!
잘 알겠소.
Agreed.
그럼 시작!
Start!
아, 저... 제 목검은 어디 있소?
Uh, what about my wooden sword-dasu?
어디서 굴러먹던 개뼈다귀인지도 모르는 놈에게 목검은 빌려주지 않는다!
We do not lend wooden swords to a stranger of doubtful origin!
덴시치로
Denshichirō
그, 그런!
No way!
오의 백조 자세!
Secret technique: swan stance!
자, 얘야, 어디서든 달려들어 보거라!
Now, kid, you may pounce from anywhere!
그렇게 말을 해도...
Even if you say so...
뭐, 이 자세에는 틈이 안 보여서 못 때리겠나?
Can't you blow a single hit against this stance?
그렇다면... 일자상전, 구멍 기만 자세라도 해 주련?
Well then, you'd like the family secret: hole deception!
아, 아니, 그런 게 아니라...
No, that's not the problem...
이것이오!
This will do-dasu!
난 이것으로 상대해 드리겠소!
I'll face you with this-dasu!
비기! 열심히 한 수고의 타격!
Mystery technique! The hit of reward for all your hard work!
흥. 얘야, 아직 갈 길이 한참 멀구나.
Hmph, kid, you still have a long way to go.
극의! 그걸로는 안 된다!는 타격.
Secret skill! The hit of letting you know that it won't work.
네이놈!
How dare you!
아직아직 약한 네 타격!
Still weak! The hit of yours!
어떻게든 내가 이긴 것 같소만.
It seems that I won-dasu.
손이 미끄러져 목검을 떨어뜨렸지만, 아직 몸은 이대로 어디 하나 다친 곳 없다!
I may have slipped the wooden sword off my hand, but my body has no single scratch whatsoever!
승부는 지금부터다, 꼬맹이!
The real match starts now, kiddo!
억지부리고 있소! 목검 없이 이 일격, 받아낼 수 있을 것이오?
Not willing to accept defeat-dasu? Try taking this strike without your wooden sword-dasu!
우리 요시오카 도장에는 궁극의 오의가 아직 있지.
We still have an ultimate secret technique left at our Yoshioka Dōjō.
그 이름도!
The name is!
진검 받아내기!
(Shinken Shirahadori: 真剣白刃取り. Stopping a sword by bare hands)
Shinken Shirahadori!
아릅답게 받아 보이시오!
You try that-dasu!
힘이 먼저 빠지는 쪽이 지는 것이군.
The first one to be exhausted first will lose!
젠장, 이대로 끝나겠소...
Damn, is this end?
어떻냐, 꼬맹이. 거기까지인 듯 하군.
How's that, kiddo? It seems that you reached your limit.
아직아직! 극의! 그대로 내리쳐서는 안 된다면 들어 보이겠소!
I'm not finished yet! Secret technique: If pressing down doesn't work, I'll raise instead-dasu!
이랴!
Here it goes!
이겼다! 드디어 세주로에게 이겼소!
I won! I finally defeated Sējūrō-dasu!
네이놈, 꼬맹이! 잘도 형님을! 이제 상관없다! 이 꼬맹이를 해치워버려라!
How dare you do that to my brother, you brat! Nothing matters now! Finish off this brat!
이러면 내가 압도적으로 불리하오. 어떻게 하지 않으면...
I'm overwhelmingly at disadvantage at this rate-dasu. I must do something...
그렇소!
That's it-dasu!
피하지 않으면 위험하오!
Move or be hit-dasu!
에잇, 뭘 하나! 빨리 가서 잡아라!
What are you doing? Follow and get him!
-도망치지 못할 테다!
-멈춰라!
-You're not running away!
-Stop right there!
도망가고 있는 것이 아니오! 이것도 작전의 하나이오!
I'm not running away-dasu! This also is a strategy-dasu!
여기라면 둘러싸일 걱정은 없소만...
I won't have to worry about being surrounded here-dasu, but...
자! 어디서든 와 보시오!
You may come from anywhere-dasu!
잡아라!
Get him!
에잇! 얘를 상대로 뭔 시간이 그리 드나!
Why are you taking so much time against a single child?
비켜라! 내가 쓰러뜨려 주겠다.
Get out of the way! I'll take him down myself.
오시오!
Come!
죽어라, 꼬맹이!
Die, you brat!
각오해라!
Prepare yourself!
-관둬라!
-뭐라?
-Stop that!
-What?
아저씨는...
You're..
네놈은 누구냐!
Who are you bastard?!
난 료마라는 사람이다.
I am Ryoma.
네이놈! 우릴 방해할 셈이냐!
Damn you! Are you going to get in the way of our battle?!
그럴 생각은 없지만, 다 자란 성인이 아이들 상대로 진검승부라니 꼴불견이로구먼.
That's not what I have in mind, but it's pretty unsightly for an adult to have a match against a kid with a real sword.
무슨 소릴, 웃기지 마라! 먼저 너부터 처리해 주겠다!
Nonsense. Don't make me laugh! You're going down first!
저런. 이 이상 오면 배 한가운데에 구멍이 뚫릴 거요.
Take another step and you'll get a hole in the middle of your stomach.
움직이지 마라.
Do not move.
자. 이 틈에 도망쳐라.
Now, run away when you have time.
그, 근데 저, 무예가로서 적에게서 달아나는 것은...
Bu- but, as a martial artist, I must not run away...
하천에 뛰어들었다!
They jumped into the river!
사라졌다!
They disappeared!
모습이 어디에도 안 보여!
We can't find him!
아, 저쪽이다!
There they are!
제군! 또 보자!
Gentlemen! See you again!
달아날까보냐, 꼬맹아! 비겁자!
Are you running away, you brat? You coward!
난 비겁자가 아니오!
I am not a coward!
덴시치로의 원한을 사고 만 무사시. 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Musashi has bought Denshichirō's wrath. Wait for the stormy latter half!
왜 그러냐? 녀석들이라면 이제 뒤쫒는 걸 관뒀으니 잘 자 두어라.
What's the problem? They gave up the pursuit, so you should be able to sleep well.
나, 료마 씨에게 구해졌으니 은혜를 갚아야 하오.
I must pay you back for saving me-dasu.
그런데 전혀 용기가 나지 않소.
But I'm not getting the courage-dasu.
뭘 고민하냐. 어린 녀석이 그렇게 고민하면 상투 벗겨진다.
You shouldn't be worrying so much. You're gonna lose your topknot if you worry so much from your youth!
나... 료마 씨에게 구해진 탓에 비겁자가 되었소.
I... have became a coward because I was saved by you, Ryoma.
자, 무사시 군. 도망가는 것은 비겁한 것도 뭣도 아니야.
Hey, Musashi. Running away isn't cowardly or something.
네게도 그 사실을 깨달을 때가 올 테지만, 달아나는 것은 더 말할 나위 없는 병법의 하나일 뿐.
You'll eventually understand that running away also is a superb tactic.
그건 수배인인 료마 씨의 병법이오!
That's the tactic of Ryoma who is a wanted man-dasu!
아...
Oh...
수배인의 병법, 그것이 좋은 것이지.
The tactic of a wanted man. That's a good thing!
저기, 료마 씨. 나, 료마 씨의 어딜 봐도 나쁜 사람으로 보이지 않소만,
Hey, Ryoma. You don't even look like a bad person,
어째서 미야코 팔레스를 부수려는 것이오?
but why are you trying to overthrow the Miyako Palace-dasu?
지팡구국에 새벽을 부르기 위해서다.
To call the dawn to Jipangu State.
어? 새벽이라면 매일 오오.
Huh? There is a dawn for every day-dasu.
그런 뜻이 아니라, 지팡구국을 전투 따위 없는 평화롭고 자유로운 나라로 만든다는 의미야.
That's what I meant. I mean that I am trying to make Jipangu State a free and peaceful place without a war.
평화를 추구하는 자가 어째서 수배당하고 말았소?
Why did you became a wanted man when you're pursuing for peace-dasu?
그렇게 되면 지금 높으신 분들이 더는 거들먹거릴 수 없게 되기 때문이지.
Once that happens, those high ranked people won't be able to be arrogant anymore.
자, 그런 어려운 이야기는 내일 하고 오늘은 슬슬 자라.
Now, let's talk about those difficult subjects tomorrow, and you should sleep now.
미야코 팔레스에는 요시오카 도장의 제자들이 무사시를 찾고 있었다.
In the Miyako Palace, disciples of Yoshioka Dōjō were looking for Musashi.
그리고 신선조는 료마를 붙잡기에 혈안이 되어 있었다.
And also, Shinsen family was desperately looking for Ryoma.
킬리만자로
Kilimanjaro
3문
3 mons
블루마운틴
Blue Mountain
5문
5 mons
콜롬비아
Columbian
3문
3 mons
감칠맛모카
Mocha Mattari
3문
3 mons
아메리카노
American
3문
3 mons
그 쯤 코지로는...
Meanwhile, Kojirō was...
나왔습니다.
Here it is.
설탕은 필요없다!
I do not need sugar!
커피에 설탕을 넣는 것은 올바르지 못하다!
Adding sugar to coffee is a heresy!
아, 네.
Oh, okay.
역시 모카구나. 이 입 안에 부드럽게 감칠맛나는 산미가 무엇보다도...
Mocha is great as always. The feeling of soft and good flavor filling my mouth...
휴게 도중에 정말 죄송하오만, 귀하는 이 자를 본 적이 있나?
I'm sorry to interrupt your rest, but did you see this guy around?
이건... 무사시잖아!
Isn't this Musashi?
알고 계신가?
Do you know?
뭐... 조금은 알지만. 이 자가 뭔 짓을 했습니까?
Well... kind of. Did he do something?
그래, 우리 요시오카 일족의 수령 세주로 님의 머리를 타격해... 읍읍
Yes. Sējūrō, our head at Yoshioka, was hit on his head by him...
뭐라?! 무사시가 요시오카의 도장의 수령을 쓰러뜨렸다고?!
What?! Musashi took down the head of Yoshioka Dōjō?
오! 귀하도 우리의 분함을 이해해 주시는가!
Oh! Are you understanding our mortification?
믿을 수가 없군. 그 요시오카 수령이 그렇게 약했다고는!
Unbelievable. I never thought the head of Yoshioka was that weak!
그럴 거였다면 어서 내가 가서 먼저 쓰러뜨렸으면 됐을 것을!
If that was the case, I could have taken him down first!
뭐라고?!
What is that?!
머리가!
My hair!
무사시 놈! 약한 주제에 운 좋은 놈!
Damn Musashi! That weak but lucky bastard!
저기, 료마 씨. 대체 날 어디에 데려갈 생각이오?
Hey, Ryoma, where are you taking me to-dasu?
새로운 지팡국을 만들기 위한 아지트다.
The hideout for making the new Jipangu State.
에? 나는 료마 씨가 하는 일이 좋지만, 악당의 동료가 되는 건 사절이오.
Huh? While I like what you're doing, I don't want to be a comrade of a villain-dasu.
TEA
차
내가 아무리 그렇다고 해도 무엇보다도 척척 본명으로 불리는 게 마음에 들어.
Even if I am one, I'd like to be called by my name.
찾아냈군, 료마.
I finally found you, Ryoma.
이곳이 내 아지트다.
This my hideout.
어머, 새로운 지팡구국을 만들기 위한 아지트치고 별 거 없는 곳이오...
Huh, it's pretty small for a hideout of making a new Jipangu State-dasu...
넌 정말로 거리낌 없는 놈이구나.
You're very outspoken guy.
뭐, 됐으니까 들어와라.
Anyway, come in.
무사시 놈, 결국엔 찾아냈다!
Musashi, I finally found you!
어서 덴시치로 스승님께 보고해야겠어!
We must report back to our master Denshichirō right away.
어라, 새로운 지팡구국을 만든다는 것은 틀림없이 싸움 준비를 한다 생각했는데...
Hey, I thought making a new Jipangu State would involve preparing for a war.
왠지 장사하고 있는 같소...
It looks like you're in a commerce-dasu.
그대로다. 일부로 장사하고 있지. 새로운 나라를 만들기 위해선 전투보다도 돈이 현실적이야.
That's right. I'm doing this on purpose. Money is more realistic than fighting to make a new country.
어떤 걸 파오?
What do you sell-dasu?
평화를 팔고 있지.
I sell peace.
평화?
Peace?
그래. 기근으로 먹을 것 없는 나라에 식료를 내리고 전장이 된
Right. We give food to a country with famine, and prepare to
마을의 사람들을 무사하게 달아나게 해 주는 준비 등을 하고 있어.
help people living in villages that became battlefields.
그것이 새로운 지팡구국을 만드는 일인 것이오?
Is that what it takes to make a new Jipangu State-dasu?
자, 무사시 군. 넌 왜 전쟁이 일어나는 지 아니?
Now, Musashi, do you know why they fight?
네?
Huh?
자원이 적으니까 모두가 빼앗으려 싸우는 거야.
They are fighting because there are not enough resources.
혹 모두가 원하는 것을 손에 넣는 것이 가능했다면...
If everyone could have anything they want...
어떠냐.
What do you think?
그것은...
That's...
싸우지 않고 살게 되오.
They will live without fighting.
바로 그거야. 내가 노리는 새로운 지팡구국은 모든 것이 풍족하고 싸움이 일어나지 않는 나라이다.
That's what I am talking about. The Jipangu State that I'm dreaming for
is the place where everything is enough and no fight occurs.
신선조 집
Shinsen Family House
뭐라? 료마의 아지트를 발견했다고?
What? You found Ryoma's hideout?
미야코 궁전 주변 농가에 들어가는 걸 이 눈으로 분명히 보았습니다.
I saw him entering a farmhouse close to the Miyako Palace with my bare eyes.
좋아. 이번이야말로 녀석에게 본때를 보여주겠어!
Great. I will show him my wrath this time!
-가자!
-예!
-Let's go!
-Got it!
모두 다! 나아가라!
Everyone! Go!
꼬맹이는 틀림없이 농가에 있다!
That brat is definitely at a farmhouse!
(주) 요시오카 도장
Yoshioka Dōjō Inc.
알겠나! 이번이야말로 반드시 붙잡는다!
Understood? We must catch him as of today!
그 일만이라도 맡기겠네.
I entrust you on this.
료마 씨 즐거워 보이오.
Mr. Ryoma, you look like you're enjoying.
내 동료가 될 생각이 들었으려나, 무사시 군.
I wonder if you want to be my comrade, Musashi.
그래도 나... 역시 카라쿠리 무예가 제일으로...
But still... I must become the number one Karakuri martial artist...
나, 최강의 무예가가 된다면 꼭 오츠루 씨를 부인으로 맞이하겠소!
When I manage to become the number one martial artist, I will marry Otsuru-dasu!
무사시 씨!
Musashi!
역시 난 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 노리겠소!
I still must aim for the number one Karakuri martial artist-dasu!
그렇구나. 그렇게 단단한 결의가 있다면 무리해서라도 나아가야지.
I see. If you're that determined, you just gotta push the limits.
꿈꾸는 바는 다르지만 목적을 완수하기 위해서는 서로 힘내자꾸나.
Even though our dreams are different, let's do our best for the objectives.
네!
Yes!
뭣이오?
What's that-dasu?
누군가 아지트 주변에 다가왔다.
Someone has come near to our hideout.
찾아냈다, 료마! 이번엔 절대 달아나지 못할 테다!
I found you, Ryoma! You're not running away from me this time!
난 아직 할 일이 많다. 너희들에게 잡힐 생각은 없어.
I still have a lot to do. I am not intending to be caught.
뭐냐, 이 연기는?!
What is this smoke?
자! 이 틈에 달아나자!
Now! Let's run away!
야, 무사시! 이번이야말로 형님의 원한을 갚아 주겠다!
Hey, Musashi! I will have revenge on you for my brother!
에, 이런 때는 오지 않았어도 됐는데!
You didn't need to come in time like this!
무사시! 각오해라!
Musashi! Prepare yourself!
-여기다!
-신선조도 따라왔구나.
-Here they are!
-It seems that Shinsen family followed us too.
료마! 각오해라!
Ryoma! Prepare yourself!
난 료마가 아니다!
I am not Ryoma!
아! 실례했다.
Excuse me.
이쪽이다! 쫒아라!
This way! Chase him!
더 이상 달아나지 못할 테다!
You're not running away any more!
이게 달아났다는 것이오?
You call this running away-dasu?
여기서 실컷 싸울 테니까!
I'll fight as much as I can here!
장소를 바꾸었을 뿐이오!
I just changed the place-dasu!
어, 어라, 료마가 아니야?
What the? He's not Ryoma!
료마는 어디냐!
Where is Ryoma?!
뭐, 뭐냐, 저건?!
What the heck is that?!
료마 씨!
Ryoma!
네이놈, 료마! 언제 그런 것을! 돌아와라, 이 비겁자!
Damn you, Ryoma! When did you come out with that?! Come back here, you coward!
걷는 것 말고 다른 방법도 생각해 보쇼, 콘도 씨.
Come up with something else than walking, Kondō.
비겁자라고 불려도 난 목적을 완수할 때까진 죽을 생각은 없다!
Even though I am called a coward, I'm not dying until I achieve what I dream!
달아나는 것은 더 말할 나위 없는 병법의 하나일 뿐.
Running away also is a superb tactic.
료마 씨! 나, 깨달았소!
Ryoma! I finally understood-dasu!
무사시, 각오해라!
Musashi, prepare yourself!
필살! 엄청 맹진!
Final blow! Extreme forward rush!
달아가는가, 무사시! 비겁자!
Are you running away, Musashi? Coward!
달아나는 것은 더 말할 나위 없는 병법의 하나이오!
Running away indeed is a superb tactic-dasu!
무사시 군, 또 보자꾸나! 지팡구국의 새벽은 가깝다!
Musashi, see you soon! The dawn of Jipangu State is soon!
바람같은 카라쿠리인 료마와의 만남은 무사시를 한 단계 크게 성장시켜 주었다.
Meeting with Ryoma, a wind-like Karakuri man, has let Musashi take a big step forward.
달려라, 무사시! 큰 뜻이 이루어질 그 날까지!
Run, Musashi! Until the day that your dreams come true!
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
쓰라린 수련을 받고 제몫을 할 무예가가 되었을 나지만,
After the painful training, I am supposed to be a martial artist worth of one's salt,
제일 중요한 검을 가지지 못했소.
but I still don't have the crucial sword-dasu.
그런 이유로 검 장인을 방문했지만, 문전박대.
Because of that I went to meet the master of sword craftsman, I was refused-dasu.
젠장! 만들어주지 않을 것이라면 내 직접 지팡구 제일의 명검을 만들겠소!
Damn! If he's not going to make me one, I'm going to make one myself-dasu!
다음 이야기! 명검 장인, 폭풍을 부르오
Next story! Master of Sword Maker Calls for a Storm-dasu.
질풍노도의 다음 이야기를 보시오!
Be sure to check out the next stormy story-dasu!
다음 이야기
명검 장인, 폭풍을 부르오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Master of Sword Maker
Calls for a Storm
Look forwards for it!